CURRICULUM VITAE

William Waweru Kariuki

OBJECTIVE

To attain a successful career in Occupational Safety by using the knowledge I have obtained together with my experience drawn from my work environment as well as involvement in various task forces, training programmes and workshops.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

2019	ASME Sec VIII Design Enginer Div 1	ITC, Dammam Saudi Arabia
2016	Non Destructive Testing Level II	Trinity Institute, Bangalore India
2008	Certificate in Environmental Impact Assessment and	Audit JKUAT, Nairobi,
2006	Industrial attachment at Kenya Railways Central Wo	rkshop KR, Nairobi
2007-2008	PGD (OSH)	JKUAT, Nairobi
1989-1992	Bachelor of Science degree	University of Nairobi

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Principal Occupational Safety and Health Officer, Occupational Safety and Health Services in charge of the Safety Division in the Directorate.

2015- Date Head of Safety Divisions
 2007 to 2015 Deputy Head of Occupational Safety Division. Chiefr Occupational Safety and Health Officer

- Conducting Safety and Health audits of workplaces
- Investigation of occupational Accidents
- Prosecution
- Supervising approved plant examiners
- Proving guidelines for inspection and testing of lifting equipment and pressure vessels
- Analysing pressure vessels/lifting equipment reports from approved persons
- o Policy formulation in area of hazardous industrial plants

- o Initiating policy, review and updating of Occupational Safety and Health Act and its subsidiary legislation in areas of lifting equipment and pressure vessels
- o Training of Employers and Employees on occupational health and safety.
- Monitors workplace environment hazards through hygiene measurements i.e.
 Noise, dust etc.
- o Enforcement of the Occupational Safety and Health Act.
- Participates in sensitizing workers and the community in workplace health hazards that affects the health and wellbeing of the workers.
- Risk assessment of workplaces.
- Management of projects/programmes for the purpose of strengthening and enhancing occupational hygiene services in the country.
- o Participating in training in the field of Occupational Safety and Health.
- Monitoring and evaluation of work environment hazards and providing recommendations for control measures.
- o Provision of specialist opinion on lifting equipment and pressure vessels
- Member of the Occupational Health and Safety Committee Work Improvement Teams (WITS). (This is the team that deals with the technical issues in occupational health and safety in the country).
- Advising employers, employees and other stakeholders on issues related to environmental safety, environmental pollution and control, health and safety of persons

SPECIAL ASSIGNMENTS

- o A member of the KEBS Technical committee of Boilers and Pressure vessels
- o A member of the KEBS Technical committee of Lifts and Escalators
- Has been a member of taskforces and committees on drafting of Liquefied Petroleum Gas regulation 2018 under Energy Act
- o Focal point for DOSHS in Kenya Petroleum Technical Assistance Project(KEPTAP).
- Secretary to Technical Advisory and Drafting Committee for formulation of Occupational safety and health regulation for petroleum sector.
- Was a member of the committee that drafted the noise reduction and control rules (2005, medical examination rules (2005) under the Factories and other Places of work Act (CAP 514) laws of Kenya in the Directorate of Occupational Safety and Health Services

OTHER PERSONAL DETAILS

Married Date of birth 1968
Nationality Kenyan

REFEREES

Dr Musa Nyandusi

Ag Director

Directorate of Occupational Health and Safety Services

P. O. Box 34120-00100

Nairobi

Cell Phone: 0724504220

Edward Mwirigi Kinyua

Director Petroleum

Energy and Petroleum Regulatory Authority

P.O. Box 42681 – 00100 Nairobi

Cell Phone:0721891498